MICHAEL MILLER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Logical and results driven Front End Developer offering 3+ years of experience. Dedicated to building and optimizing user-focused websites for customers with various business objectives. Judicious and creative when crafting effective websites, apps and platforms to propel competitive advantage and revenue growth. Technically proficient and analytical problem solver with calm and focused demeanor.

WORK HISTORY

Full-Stack Developer, 06/2019 to 04/2020 MicroSurgical Technology - Redmond, WA

- Delivered performance-driven and user-centric websites that met all business requirements.
- Ensured accessibility of site for visually impaired using semantic HTML5 and JavaScript.
- Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.
- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for creating well-organized project plans.
- Oversaw full lifecycle software development with 100% on-time delivery.

Web Developer, 12/2018 to 05/2019 AirTech Heating & Air - Beaufort, SC

- Oversaw web platform testing, troubleshooting and user sampling prior to live deployment.
- Developed functional digital design concepts across various platforms to strengthen company brand and identity.
- Established presentation consistency across Chrome, Safari, Firefox and other common browser interfaces.
- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages, plugins and functionality for continuous improvement.

Freelance Web Developer, 06/2017 to 12/2018 Upwork.com

- Designed & developed a two-way SMS communication appointment scheduling microservice.
- Created and maintained multiple intranet websites, managing external resources as needed.
- Involved in the website architecture design; developed highly user interactive web pages with HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

EDUCATION

B.S., Information & Computer Science Park University

CONTACT

Address: Mercer Island, WA 98040

Phone: (843) 263-8722

Email: memiller219@gmail.com
Portfolio: www.memillerdev.com
https://github.com/memiller219

GitHub:

SKILLS

- HTML / JavaScript / CSS
- React / Redux
- MySQL
- Node.js
- UX & UI Design
- SEO
- Agile/SCRUM Methodologies